hobbytown.com 2009-12-31

# HobbyTown USA | Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy  
  
---  
  
Thank you for visiting [www.hobbytown.com](http://www.hobbytown.com/). This site is governed by the Privacy Policy of Hobby Town Unlimited, Inc. ("HobbyTown USA® ") and discloses the consumer privacy practices of the [www.hobbytown.com](http://www.hobbytown.com/) website ("HOBBYTOWN USA's Online Catalog"). Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy, we provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used at this site.

You can freely access much of our website without providing any personal information. Certain areas of our website, for example purchasing products, entering contests, filling out surveys, and receiving newsletters, emails or other promotional information from us, require that you submit some personal information. We do not collect any personal information without your knowledge! We use the information that we collect about you to fulfill your product and service purchases and to create a more personalized online experience.

This is just a brief overview, so please read on for more details about our Privacy Policy. This Policy may change from time to time, so please check back periodically.

Questions regarding this Policy should be directed to [privacy@hobbytown.com](mailto:privacy@hobbytown.com) or may also be contacted directly at the following address: 

**Attn: Privacy Compliance Officer  
HobbyTown USA®  
6301 S. 58th Street  
Lincoln, NE 68516**

What information do HOBBYTOWN USA's websites collect from you?  
  
In order to better provide you with numerous products and services, HOBBYTOWN USA's websites collects two types of information about its visitors: Personally Identifiable Information and Non-Personally Identifiable Information. Our primary goal in collecting information from you is to provide you with a smooth, efficient, and customized experience while using our site.

**Personally Identifiable Information**

This refers to information that lets us know the specifics of who you are. Personal information is requested when you order a product, register for a Wish List, enter contests or sweepstakes, fill out surveys, and send us feedback. For example, this information might include your name, billing address, shipping address, telephone number, email address, credit card or other payment information, and product details. With this information, HOBBYTOWN USA's Online Catalog can fill your orders and better provide you with personalized services.

If you visit HOBBYTOWN USA or one of the sites available through a link on our site, they will independently collect, use and share your personal information in accordance with their own privacy policies. If you have questions about their information practices, please read their privacy policies.

**Non-Personally Identifiable Information**

This refers to information that does not by itself identify a specific individual. We gather certain information about you based upon where you shop on our site in several ways. This information is compiled and analyzed on both a personal and an aggregated basis. For example, this information may include the website's Uniform Resource Locator ("URL") that you just came from, which URL you next go to, what browser you are using, and your Internet Protocol ("IP") address. A URL is the global address of documents and other resources on the World Wide Web. An IP address is an identifier for a computer or device on a Transmission Control Protocol/Internet Protocol ("TCP/IP") network, such as the World Wide Web. Networks like the Web use the TCP/IP protocol to route information based on the IP address of the destination. In other words, an IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the web, allowing web servers to locate and identify your computer. Computers require IP addresses in order for users to communicate on the Internet, browse and shop.  
  
Where do we collect information from you and how do we use it?  
  
Our primary goal in collecting personal information is to provide HOBBYTOWN USA's website visitors with a superior customized online experience. We use the customer contact information to fill orders, contact purchasers to inform them of their order status, to send promotional information, to enhance the operation of our site and administer our systems.

We review the actions of the HOBBYTOWN USA's website visitors on an aggregate basis to determine customers' preferences. HOBBYTOWN USA's website also does research on our visitors' demographics, interests, and pages viewed based on the information provided to us during ordering, a promotion, from our server log files, from contests, drawings or surveys. We will use this data to tailor the visitor's experience at our site, to improve our marketing and promotional efforts, to statistically analyze site use, to improve our product offerings, and to customize our site's content, layout, and services.

HOBBYTOWN USA's website also shares your personally identifiable information with HOBBYTOWN USA and third parties who provide services to us, our customers and website visitors. Those third parties include authorized contractors, temporary employees and consultants and other companies working with us (collectively, "agents"). Where we believe it to be appropriate (in our sole discretion), we will ask our agents not to disclose or use your personal information for purposes other than to provide services to you or HOBBYTOWN USA's websites.

Although we take appropriate measures to safeguard against unauthorized disclosures of information, we cannot assure you that personally identifiable information that we collect will never be disclosed in a manner that is inconsistent with this Privacy Notice. Inadvertent disclosures may result, for example, when third parties misrepresent their identities in asking the site for access to personally identifiable information about themselves for purposes of correcting possible factual errors in the data.  
  
We gather information in the following ways:  
  
**Shopping**

We collect IP addresses for the purposes of system administration, to gather broad demographic information, to report Non-Personally Identifiable Information to HOBBYTOWN USA, and to monitor the level of activity on our site. We collect information from visitors to our site regarding the URLs they came from, domain types (e.g., .com or .org), their IP addresses, the date and time of their visit or order, the number of visits and orders, the number of visits per browsing session, the server type, the operating system and browser type used to come to the site, the country, state and telephone area code where their servers are located, the pages and page titles of our site that visitors viewed during their visit, whether the visitor's computer is enabled for Java or cookies, browser language, applications and plug-ins, and any search terms entered on our site.

**Ordering**

When you order from HOBBYTOWN USA's Online Catalog, we collect personally identifiable information from you. If you order one of our products, we will collect and maintain your name, email address, billing address, shipping address, telephone number, product selections, credit card or other payment information, order number, referring URL, IP address, page you bought from and a password. We collect this, and other information, as disclosed in this Policy, in order to fill your order, to communicate with you about your order and to send you promotional materials. Before confirming your order, you will have the opportunity to review the product order form and make changes and additions to the information it contained and these changes will be automatically kept for future use.

**Online Surveys and Polling**

In order to improve our services to you, we ask some of our customers to voluntarily complete surveys. Individual survey answers are confidential, although Non-Personally Identifiable Information is collected and disclosed to third parties. If you do not wish to participate in a survey, simply decline to participate when asked.

**Contests and Sweepstakes**

When you enter a contest or other promotion, we may ask you for contact information such as your name, address and email address in order to administer the contest, to send you promotional emails, notify winners and make the winners' list publicly available pursuant to certain states' laws. Your consent to such promotional use and disclosure of this information is a condition of your participation. As a condition of receiving any prize, you will be required to submit an Affidavit of Eligibility, for us to ensure that you are eligible to receive the prize according to the Contest Rules.

**Newsletters & Promotional Emails**

We offer free newsletters and promotional emails as a service to our customers. We will send you newsletters and emails periodically listing current specials and deals. To stop receiving our newsletter, send an email to us at marketing@hobbytown.com.

**Contact Information and Third Party Data**

If you contact HOBBYTOWN USA's website or our customer service representatives by telephone, email or letter, we may keep a record of your correspondence or comments. If you report a problem with our site, we may collect such information in a file specific to you. If you contact us through our feedback area or by calling one of our customer service representatives, we may ask for your name, email address and order information in order to send you a reply. If other users or third parties send us correspondence about your activities or purchases on our site, we may keep the information in a file specific to you.

**Site Activity**

We also track customers' traffic patterns throughout their online session, including which pages, information and advertisements a customer views while using the site and what items they place in their basket or purchase. We use your IP address to diagnose problems with our servers, software, to administer our site and to gather demographic information.

We may share aggregated statistics about pages viewed on our site, sales and other shopping information with third parties.

**Cookies**

HOBBYTOWN USA's website may use cookies from time to time. Cookies are small text files a website can use to recognize a repeat visitor to the website. We use cookies for various reasons. Cookies enable us to provide you with a better experience by allowing us to understand what areas of this Site are of interest to our members. These cookies do not track individual information. Cookies from HOBBYTOWN USA's website can only be read by HOBBYTOWN USA's websites. If you do not want HOBBYTOWN USA's website to deploy cookies in your browser, you can set your browser to reject cookies or to notify you when a website tries to put a cookie in your browser software. If you choose to disable cookies in your browser, you can still access most of this Site, however, your ability to use some of the products and/or services, including the shopping cart, at this Site may be affected.

**Action Tags**

We may use action tags in the operation of our site. An action tag is a method used to track responses or actions by customers who view certain information on our site. Action tags are images embedded in a website page that are used to transparently collect information. Our content servers may use action tags to count the number of times that visitors click on a particular page section or visit the pages of our site. Without collecting any personally identifiable information, they use that data to tell us which are the most effective sections of our sites.

Email Distributor's Use of Action Tags: Our third-party email distributor may use action tags. They may, for example, keep track of when a promotional email is opened and provide HOBBYTOWN USA's Online Catalog with ongoing aggregated reports of how many customers have responded.

On occasion, unaffiliated third parties will "frame" HOBBYTOWN USA's website site in an effort to collect customer information. To ensure your privacy, make sure that your order originates from HOBBYTOWN USA's website. HOBBYTOWN USA's website is not in any manner responsible in the event that you do disclose information to an unaffiliated framing site.  
  
With whom do we share your information?  
  
_Fulfillment:_ The information collected by HOBBYTOWN USA's website is used for processing orders, keeping you informed about your order status, for statistical purposes, for improving our site and its performance, and to notify you of products or special offers that may be of interest to you. We will disclose your Personally Identifiable Information to HOBBYTOWN USA. Additionally we will disclose your Personally Identifiable Information to third parties to charge your credit card, fill your order, deliver your order, provide customer service, provide you with credit and deliver promotional emails to you from HOBBYTOWN USA's website. For example, we must release your credit card information to the card-issuing bank to confirm payment; and release your address and telephone information to the delivery service to deliver products that you ordered.

_Other Parties:_ We do not sell, trade, or rent your Personally Identifiable Information to others without your consent. We may provide Non-Personally Identifiable Information about our customers' sales, traffic patterns, and related site information to third parties, but these statistics do not include any Personally Identifiable Information. We may release account information when we believe that such release is reasonably necessary to enforce or apply our Terms and Conditions or to protect the rights, property, and safety of HOBBYTOWN USA's website, our users, or others. If customers do not pay us for products ordered, we may submit their account information to a third party collection agency.

_Compliance with Service of Process or Law Enforcement:_ Occasionally HOBBYTOWN USA's website may be asked by law enforcement or judicial authorities to provide Personally Identifiable Information to the appropriate governmental authorities. We will disclose Personally Identifiable Information upon receipt of a court order, subpoena, or to cooperate with a law enforcement investigation, without prior notice to you. HOBBYTOWN USA's website fully cooperates with law enforcement agencies in identifying those who use our services for illegal activities. We reserve the right to report to law enforcement agencies any activities that we in good faith believe to be unlawful.  
  
How can you update or correct your Personally Identifiable Information?  
  
We believe you should have the ability to access and edit the personal information that you have provided to us. During the online ordering process you can review, change, or delete the information that you have submitted. You may change any of your personal information in your account online at any time. We encourage you to promptly update your information if it changes. You may ask to have the information on your account deleted or removed; however, because we keep track of past purchases, you cannot delete information associated with past purchases. Also, as a security measure we "back up" the data stored on our systems, and such prior information cannot be completely removed from our databases. As a result, you should not expect that all of your Personally Identifiable Information will be completely removed from our backed-up databases.  
  
What are your choices regarding collection, use, and distribution of your information?  
  
_Email:_ We may from time to time send you email or other communications regarding current promotions, specials and new additions to the HOBBYTOWN USA's website. You may "opt-out," or unsubscribe from our newsletters by following the unsubscribe instructions in any email you receive from us, or by sending an email to marketing@hobbytown.com. After doing so, HOBBYTOWN USA's website users will not receive future communications or mailings unless they opt-in, open a new account or enter a contest.

_Cookies:_ You may also set your browser so that it will not accept "cookies" to prevent assignment of a unique identifier; however, you will be unable to shop on our site if you do so.  
  
What security precautions are in place to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of your information?  
  
In order to most efficiently serve you, credit card transactions and order fulfillment are handled by established third party banking, processing agents and distribution institutions. They receive the information needed to verify and authorize your credit card or other payment information and to process and ship your order.

When you access your account information, the information is kept on a secure server. All of the customer data we collect is protected against unauthorized access by physical security means.  
  
A special note about children's privacy  
  
You must be at least 18 years old to have our permission to use this site. Our policy is that we do not knowingly collect, use or disclose Personally Identifiable Information about visitors under 18 years of age. If you are the parent or guardian of a minor under 18 years of age and believe that they have disclosed personally identifiable information to us, please contact us at privacy@hobbyshopnow.com so that we may delete the minor's information.

You should carefully review privacy policies of HobbyTown USA® and any third party sites accessible from HOBBYTOWN USA's website.

HOBBYTOWN USA and other sites accessible through our website have their own privacy policies and data collection, use and disclosure practices. Please consult each site's privacy policy. HOBBYTOWN USA's website is not responsible for the policies or practices of third parties. Please be aware that this site may contain links to other sites on the Internet that are owned and operated by third parties. The information practices of those websites linked to HOBBYTOWN USA's website are not covered by this Privacy Policy. These other sites may send their own cookies to users, collect data, or solicit personal information.  
  
Contacting HOBBYTOWN USA's websites about privacy questions or concerns  
  
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this site, please contact HOBBYTOWN USA's website by sending a letter to:

**Attn: Privacy Compliance Officer  
HobbyTown USA®  
6301 S. 58th Street  
Lincoln, NE 68516**

You may also contact us by email at [privacy@hobbytown.com](mailto:privacy@hobbytown.com)  
  
Privacy Policy changes  
  
This Privacy Policy was last changed on June 1, 2002. If HOBBYTOWN USA's websites make changes to any terms or conditions of the Privacy Policy, the changes will be posted in this document so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information and to whom we will disclose it. We may change, modify, add or remove portions of this Policy at any time, and any changes will become effective immediately upon being posted unless we tell you otherwise.
